<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Learn Rubix Blockchain Platform</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Learn Rubix Blockchain Platform</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://learn.rubix.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>API EndPoints</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/api/</guid><description>User communicates with the node thats running in the background via REST APIs. Below listed are the REST API Endpoints with which user can able to view information, transfer tokens and so on.
Rubix Node Setup Field Endpoint Description Sample Request DID Creation /createDID Creates a unique Decentralized IDentity curl --location --request POST 'http://localhost:1898/create' --form 'data=&amp;quot;Rubik&amp;quot;' --form 'image=@&amp;quot;imagepath&amp;quot;' Initial Setup /start Does the initial setup of IPFS and syncing the network nodes.</description></item><item><title>Setup Rubix Node</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/node-setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/node-setup/</guid><description>Nodes in Rubix mine tokens by utilizing credits earned by validating transactions in the network.
When a new node joins the network, it will have 0 credits and 0 tokens to start with. Over the time common pool will pick the node to validate transactions coming to the network. For every transaction that is validated, the node will earn 1 credit. Credits are non transferable and are only used to mine a new RBT token.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://learn.rubix.net/linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/linux/</guid><description>Linux Download the setup for installing all the dependencies for setting up Rubix node from the link below.
Linux
Open a fresh instance of terminal under download path and run the following commands (without $)
a) $ chmod +x RubixOneClickSetup-Linux
b) $ ./RubixOneClickSetup-Linux
c) Provide user password when asked
After the setup is completed open a new terminal and try the following commands (without $) :</description></item><item><title/><link>https://learn.rubix.net/macos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/macos/</guid><description>MacOS Download the setup for installing all the dependencies for setting up Rubix node from the link below.
MacOS
Open a fresh instance of terminal under download path and run the following commands (without $)
a) $ chmod +x RubixOneClickSetup-MacOS
b) $ ./RubixOneClickSetup-MacOS
c) Provide user password when asked
After the setup is completed open a new terminal and try the following commands (without $) :</description></item><item><title/><link>https://learn.rubix.net/windows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/windows/</guid><description>Windows Download the setup for installing all the dependencies for setting up Rubix node from the link below.
Windows
Open a fresh instance of cmd.exe under the download path and run the following commands (without $)
a) $ RubixOneClickSetup-Windows.exe
b) Provide user password when asked
After the setup is completed open a new command prompt and try the following commands (without $) :
a) $ ipfs &amp;ndash;version</description></item><item><title>Additional Rubix review</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/additional-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/additional-review/</guid><description>What are Rubix Notes? Rubix Notes is a pilot program that allows voluntary contributors on Rubix to collaboratively add context (called “notes”) to Tweets they believe could be misleading. The aim is to keep people better informed about Rubix by showing notes that people from different points of view will find helpful.
Notes are only shown to a small set of people in the pilot program, and notes only appear on Tweets when they’ve been rated helpful by enough people from different points of view.</description></item><item><title>Bring your own BlockSpace</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/blockspace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/blockspace/</guid><description>If you are familiar with blockspaces, skip to BlockSpace in Rubix.
What is blockspace? Blockspace is the number of transactions which the blockchain will order before appending to the chain of previous transactions. For example, if max block space is 200KB and an average transaction takes only 1Kb, then the chain may have a room for ~190 transactions in one block. Blockspace is a measure of how busy is the blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Cold Wallet</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/coldwallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/coldwallet/</guid><description>A cold wallet is a cryptocurrency storage wallet that is not connected to the internet, making it difficult to remotely steal the assets it stores. They keep the user&amp;rsquo;s address and private key safe while allowing them to view their portfolio without compromising their private keys. Cold wallets are the safest way to store your crypto assets. They usually require a bit of knowledge to set up. With cold storage, the generation and storage of private keys is done offline.</description></item><item><title>Common Issues</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/CommonIssues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/CommonIssues/</guid><description>1. Token Transer failed from MacOS GUI Wallet to Linux Node. Error message :
Socket timeout
Issue :
MacOS sender not able to connect to the Linux receiver. The Linux wallet which was trying to be reached out to was corrupted, as it was inappropriately recreated at an earlier time.
To verify error :
Run the following commands on the Linux machine:
&amp;quot; $ cat Rubix/Data/DID.json &amp;quot; &amp;quot; $ jq &amp;lsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Create Decentralized IDentity</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/create-did/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/create-did/</guid><description>Decentralized IDentity is a trust framework in which identifiers, such as usernames, can be replaced with IDs that are self-owned, independent and enable data exchange using blockchain technology to protect privacy and secure the transactions. As our lives are increasingly linked to apps, devices and services we are often subject to data breaches and privacy loss. A standards-based Decentralized IDentity system can provide greater privacy and control over your data.</description></item><item><title>Datum</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/datum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/datum/</guid><description>Data Storage Data storage is indispensable to every active user, be it business or individual. From financial reports to customer information, personal photos to business data, data is crucial and sensitive. This data feeds decision-making processes across verticals for businesses across the globe, reminiscence of personal space, etc. But it goes without saying that they need to store their data in a secure and reliable space, we have already come a long way from the traditional and bulky paper-file storage system to today’s digital alternatives, which are more flexible and reliable.</description></item><item><title>Decentralized IDentity</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/did/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/did/</guid><description>DID &amp;amp; its significance DID (Decentralized identity) is a trust framework in which identifiers such as usernames can be replaced with IDs that are self-owned, independent, and enable data exchange using blockchain technology, providing privacy and secure transactions. Our lives are increasingly linked to apps, devices and services, and we’re often subject to data breaches and privacy loss. Hence, a standards-based decentralized identity system can provide greater privacy and control over your data.</description></item><item><title>Downloading data</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/download-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/download-data/</guid><description>We can&amp;rsquo;t wait to learn with you!
All Rubix contributions are publicly available on the Download Data page of the Rubix site so that anyone in the US has free access to analyze the data, identify problems and spot opportunities to make Rubix better.
If you have questions/feedback about the Rubix public data or if you would like to share analysis of this data with us, please DM us at @rubixchain.</description></item><item><title>Earn Proof Credits</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/proof-credits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/proof-credits/</guid><description>Validators will accumulate proof credits from various transactions across different Proofchains. A validator node can be choosen as Alpha, Beta or as a Gamma node. Alpha nodes are picked based on the credits they have accumulated. When a node accumulates enough Proof Credits equivalent to the current level, the node can convert the proof credits into one new RBT token. Nodes continue to earn proof credits &amp;amp; thereby mine new RBT tokens by participating in consensus of various transactions &amp;amp; perpetually storing the consensus proofs.</description></item><item><title>Easily integrate your app with Rubix Blockchain Platform with Rubix SDKs</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/sdk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/sdk/</guid><description>The SDK is a set of libraries that allow developers to build applications and perform transactions directly on the Rubix blockchain platform. It includes all API calls required, as well as a full-node test client, which allows developers to run tests without running an actual node.
SDKs are designed to allows developers to quickly, easily and securely integrate their applications with the rubix blockchain platform. The SDK supports both public and subnet blockchain transactions and allows developers to build smarter applications which can act on real-time data, thereby enabling cryptoeconomics.</description></item><item><title>Examples</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/examples/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/examples/</guid><description>Great Rubix notes follow the program&amp;rsquo;s values: They build understanding, are written in good faith and are helpful even to those who disagree.
&amp;ldquo;Whales aren&amp;rsquo;t real&amp;rdquo; Here&amp;rsquo;s a Tweet making misleading claims about whales, followed by helpful and unhelpful rubix notes:
Whales are not actually mammals. If Humans (land mammals) can’t drink seawater — just try it! — how can supposed sea mammals like whales stay hydrated?</description></item><item><title>FAQs</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/faq/</guid><description>What is the support email to reach out to regarding the RBT Wallet? Users can reach out to maintainers@rubix.net for questions regaridng RBT Wallet. How many transactions can rubix handle? Monolithic blockchains like BTC and ETH scale linearly by chaining blocks of transactions sequentially. The longest chain always represents the truth. This monolithic architecture though limits how many transactions can be processed concurrenty. Ethereum for example handles around 2,000 txns in a block (from a global pool of txns).</description></item><item><title>Fexr</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/fexr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/fexr/</guid><description>Storing keys in a wallet that is not connected to the internet protects the keys from unauthorized access, Fexr introduces Crypto Wallet and On-Chain Verifiable Claims using DID. Fexr is a Non-Custodian Wallet so your Private Keys are held by you and not by any third party making you be your own bank, being build over Rubix Chain letting the user generate and store Private and Public keys on their device itself offline.</description></item><item><title>Hot Backups</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/hotbackups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/hotbackups/</guid><description>Hot backup, also known as dynamic or online backup, is performed on data while the database is actively online and accessible to users. It is useful to revert back to the previous state of the node, in the event of an undesired situation.
A backup can be simply done by creating a zip folder of the Wallet and .ipfs folders on your system.
Subsquently, a restore can be done by unzipping the same folders, to restore the previous state of your system (node).</description></item><item><title>How to verify checksum of Rubix files</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/checksum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/checksum/</guid><description>A checksum is a special type of hash that is used to verify the integrity of a file. Verifying a checksum ensures there was no corruption or manipulation during the download and the file was downloaded completely and correctly.
A common use case for checksum verification is to verify a large downloaded file. MD5 and SHA1 hashes are commonly used for this task. We will look at easy ways to obtain a hash to verify a checksum.</description></item><item><title>IPFS and Peer ID</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/ipfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/ipfs/</guid><description>IPFS (Interplanetary File System) IPFS is a relatively new hypermedia protocol and decentralized data storage system that leverages a peer-to-peer (p2p) network architecture.
By comparison, IPFS uses content-based addressing so that content can be verified and decoupled from distant servers, and stored closer to the user. It does that through the use of content identifiers (CIDs), or “labels” which are used to point to material in IPFS. CIDs are generated based on the content’s cryptographic hash, or a function that uses mathematical algorithms to take some arbitrary input and return a fixed-length value.</description></item><item><title>Key Management</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/keymanagement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/keymanagement/</guid><description>Key management is a set of practices and rules that ensure the safe use of cryptographic keys. Proper management ensures a key stays safe throughout its lifecycle, from generation and use to storing and deletion.
A cryptographic key is a file that contrails a string of letters and numbers that can encrypt and decrypt data when processed by a crypto algorithm. The main goal of key management is to keep these files away from unauthorized users and systems.</description></item><item><title>Mine ID</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/mine-id/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/mine-id/</guid><description>Our team is currently busy writing this content, we&amp;rsquo;ll update the contents here soon!!
Whales are not actually mammals. If Humans (land mammals) can’t drink seawater — just try it! — how can supposed sea mammals like whales stay hydrated?
&amp;mdash; rubix Example (@bwatchexample) January 25, 2021 -- If you have questions or feedback, please DM us at @rubixchain.
What happens when the mining level upgrades? Credits required to mine a RBT doubles every time the mining level increases.</description></item><item><title>NFT Deep Dive</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/nft-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/nft-deep-dive/</guid><description>This section explains how to initiate an NFT transaction. A good understanding of NFT and RAC is expected before diving deep into this section.
1. Enabling NFT For an existing or new user to be able to create and transfer NFTs they should first see if the Rubix node is enabled/compatible for NFT transactions. To enable NFT wallet for a new or existing user of Rubix, execute the below curl command:</description></item><item><title>NLSS</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/nlss/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/nlss/</guid><description>Non-Linear Secret Sharing (NLSS) scheme is used for creating public network share and private network share from DID. In a secret sharing scheme, a set of parties share a common secret. The information about the secret a single party owns is called a secret share. During the splitting of DID, two such shares are created. Secret shares are created from shares using some arithmetic function which can be either linear or non-linear.</description></item><item><title>Node</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/node/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/node/</guid><description>What is node? A node in the context of a Blockchain usually refers to a device that downloads the appropriate cryptocurrency software to connect to a network between partners. Any user who has completed the Rubix Network Setup will be a node in the Rubix Network. Rubix node is configured in P2P networks, each device that participates in the network receives the name of node.
The nodes are the individual parts of the largest data structure that is a blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Non Fungible Tokens</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/nft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/nft/</guid><description>NFTs are the new sensation in the world of Blockchain and cryptocurrencies. From the first NFT &amp;ldquo;Quantum&amp;rdquo; being created in 2014 to the latest NFT drop by sports giant Adidas and to NFTs that are minted on Rubix Platform.
What is an NFT? NFT stands for Non-Fungible Token. The word Fungible means Replaceable, so the meaning of NFT can be interpreted as Non-Replaceable Token, i.e an NFT is unique and each NFT is one of it&amp;rsquo;s kind.</description></item><item><title>Oracle</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/oracle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/oracle/</guid><description>-- Whales are not actually mammals. If Humans (land mammals) can’t drink seawater — just try it! — how can supposed sea mammals like whales stay hydrated?
&amp;mdash; rubix Example (@bwatchexample) January 25, 2021 -- Oracle keeps a record of the nodes in the network, credits owned by the quorums and the next token to be mined. It also performs integrity check every few seconds to ensure that all the nodes getting registered in the network get a chance to become a member of the quorum.</description></item><item><title>Private Share</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/private-share/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/private-share/</guid><description>Private Share is the second share/part of a node&amp;rsquo;s Decentalized ID (DID). It is generated during the DID&amp;rsquo;s Share generation process, and it is 8 times the size of the DID. This Share generation process uses a NLSS based cryptographic solution.
Significance: The Private Share is private/secret for a particular node and only that node has its information. Hence, it is an important parameter during different kinds of authentication scenarios.</description></item><item><title>Proof-of-Pledge</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/pop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/pop/</guid><description>Proof of Pledge (PoP) is a revolutionary protocol designed to bring the bet of both proof of work (PoW) and proof of stake (PoS). PoW is essential for security of a decentralized network. However, unlike the highly energy intensive PoW in Bitcoin &amp;amp; Ethereum, Rubix validators are required to work to verify cryptographic proofs of the Proofchains &amp;amp; produce new cryptographic work to sign the transactions. This work of validators in validating the transactions is translated into Proof Credits.</description></item><item><title>Proofchain / Token chain</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/proofchain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/proofchain/</guid><description>The Rubix global state will be made of about 51.4 million Proofchains also called as token chains. Each Proofchain is bound by one unique utility token. A Proofchain PT is made of all transactions that use token Tn to confirm. All transactions within a Proofchain PT are validated individually and sequentially. However, transactions of different Proofchains are validated asynchronously and parallelly.
If you have questions or feedback, please DM us at @rubixchain.</description></item><item><title>Public Share</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/public-share/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/public-share/</guid><description>Every node joining the Rubix platform creates a unique network Decentralized Identity (DID). This DID is then split into two shares: Public Share and Private Share. The Public Share is also reffered to as the &amp;lsquo;Public Network Share&amp;rsquo;.
Significance: The Public Netwrok Share along with the DID is stored by the node on the IPFS. The IPFS hashes of these two values are then communicated to all peer nodes in the network.</description></item><item><title>Quorum</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/quorum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/quorum/</guid><description>Quorum, as the word defines is a group of selected peers who are active in the Rubix Network that validate any transcation happening over the network. Token verification and signing is done using Rubix&amp;rsquo;s consensus algorithm &amp;lsquo;Proof of Plegde&amp;rsquo;.
There are a minimum of 21 such validators, comprising alpha quorum (⍺), beta quorum (β) and gamma quorum (γ), seven each. Out of these, alpha validators are chosen by the transacting nodes based on the combined proof credits while the remaining 14 (including 7 beta validators &amp;amp; 7 gamma validators) are chosen by each of the participating nodes respectively.</description></item><item><title>RAC - Rubix Asset Contract</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/rac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/rac/</guid><description>The Rubix Asset Contract (RAC) are rules / guidelines to enable users to develop tokens on top of Rubix Blockchain network resulting in Secondary Layer solutions, Decentralized Applications, NFTs and much more. It is a standard by which users can mint/transfer/verify secondary tokens or NFTs transfer/transact through the Rubix validator network.
Tokens minted in the Rubix network need to adhere to rules stated in the Rubix Asset Contract. These rules/guidelines may include details on what the token structure should look like, how they can be transferred in the network, validated by the quorum and so on.</description></item><item><title>Signatures and Validation</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/signature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/signature/</guid><description>Whales are not actually mammals. If Humans (land mammals) can’t drink seawater — just try it! — how can supposed sea mammals like whales stay hydrated?
&amp;mdash; rubix Example (@bwatchexample) January 25, 2021 -- Signatures are used by the sender and the quorum members during the validation of any transaction. During a token transfer, sender sends details of the token to the quorum, that consists of 21 nodes, 15 active nodes in the quorum will validate the transaction.</description></item><item><title>Staking</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/staking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/staking/</guid><description>As per the latest version, a new staking policy is introduced where it is ensured that for each new RBT mining transaction, 3 out of 5 alpha quorums pledge 1 RBT for a height of 4 difficulty level. Tokens pledged/staked will earn yield based on demand/supply. The pledged tokens will be available for transfer after completion of 256 transactions (Level 4) from the genesis node of the mined token.
If you have questions or feedback, please DM us at @rubixchain.</description></item><item><title>Subnets</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/subnets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/subnets/</guid><description>Subnet is a key construct in the Rubix architecture. The Rubix mainnet is a sum of all its subnets. Subnets can be of two types (a) private subnets: private Subnets are constructed by application providers or enterprises &amp;amp; consist of chosen validator nodes. Private subnets can be thought as private chains on a public network (b) pooled or common Subnets: Pooled or common subnets can be operated by anyone, composed of several individual nodes or pools of nodes.</description></item><item><title>Terminology</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/terminologies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/terminologies/</guid><description>We are trying to explain some of the terminalogies in simpler terms, thus you will be able to comprehend the terms more easily and swift through the process with ease
Whales are not actually mammals. If Humans (land mammals) can’t drink seawater — just try it! — how can supposed sea mammals like whales stay hydrated?
&amp;mdash; rubix Example (@bwatchexample) January 25, 2021 -- If you have questions or feedback, please DM us at @rubixchain.</description></item><item><title>Token</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/token/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/token/</guid><description>Token is used as a synonym for cryptocurrency. Every transaction in Rubix network is bound to one or set of tokens. There are two types of tokens:
Utility tokens Asset tokens Utility tokens Utility tokens are equal in their utility to validate a transaction. These are fungible and their value is independent of the work done on the Proofchain. Rubix has 51.4 million such RBT tokens.
Asset tokens Asset tokens are Non-Fungible Tokens (NFT) and represent both:</description></item><item><title>Vision</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/vision/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/vision/</guid><description>Rubix is a peer-to-peer, immutable &amp;amp; truly decentralized blockchain platform that can scale significantly with asynchronous parallelism and support real-world decentralized applications. Rubix deploys a superior consensus mechanism ‘Proof-of-Pledge’ (PoP) — a lightweight algorithm, which reduces carbon emissions significantly. The PoP is highly scalable as it can run on laptops, desktops, and other IoT devices. Its on-chain validation makes the network immutable. The platform also offers instant validation and finality of transactions with a speed of 253.</description></item><item><title>Wallet</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/wallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/wallet/</guid><description>Web2 Wallet Web2 wallets are centralized wallets where a central third-party maintains ultimate authority over the wallet transactions. Some examples of centralized cryptocurrency exchanges include Binance, Coinbase and LocalBitcoins. Web2 wallets can be related to a bank setup, where a customer trusts the bank to hold his or her money.
Web3 Wallet Web3 wallets are decentralized wallets which have the ability to store the digital assets. This includes everything from fungible to non fungible tokens.</description></item><item><title>What inspired us</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/inspired/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/inspired/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Where to buy Rubix Tokens - RBT</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/buy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/buy/</guid><description>Rubix Tokens are available to purchase in the following exchanges:
Vindax Lbank WhiteBIT If you have questions or feedback, please DM us at @rubixchain.</description></item><item><title>📣 What's New</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/whatsnew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/whatsnew/</guid><description>What is new in Rubix Network Watch this space to get the updates about all that is happening @ Rubix!!!
🎉 Rubix 2.6: Yamato We are excited to announce our latest update, Rubix 2.6: Yamato. This new update transforms the way tokens are used on our platform. We introduce faster token transfers with less number of quorums (Only 5 out of 7 quorums have to sign), pledging/un-pledging of tokens to enforce PoP to the next level of accurate tracking of token transfers with improved security, enhanced authentication using secp256k1 parameterized ECDSA key pairs, and transaction validation.</description></item></channel></rss>