<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Learn Rubix Blockchain Platform</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Learn Rubix Blockchain Platform</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://learn.rubix.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setup Rubix Node</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/node-setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/node-setup/</guid><description>Nodes in Rubix mine token by utilizing credits earned by validating transactions in the network.
When a new node joins the network, it will have 0 credits and 0 tokens to start with. Over time common pool will pick the node to validate transactions coming to the network. For every transaction that is validated, the node will earn 1 credit. Credits are non transferable and are only used to mine a new RBT token.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://learn.rubix.net/linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/linux/</guid><description>Linux Download the setup for installing all the dependencies for setting up Rubix node from the link below.
Linux
Open a fresh instance of terminal under download path and run the following commands (without $)
a) $ chmod +x RubixOneClickSetup-Linux
b) $ ./RubixOneClickSetup-Linux
c) Provide user password when asked
After the setup is completed open a new terminal and try the following commands (without $) :</description></item><item><title/><link>https://learn.rubix.net/macos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/macos/</guid><description>MacOS Download the setup for installing all the dependencies for setting up Rubix node from the link below.
MacOS
Open a fresh instance of terminal under download path and run the following commands (without $)
a) $ chmod +x RubixOneClickSetup-MacOS
b) $ ./RubixOneClickSetup-MacOS
c) Provide user password when asked
After the setup is completed open a new terminal and try the following commands (without $) :</description></item><item><title/><link>https://learn.rubix.net/windows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/windows/</guid><description>Windows Download the setup for installing all the dependencies for setting up Rubix node from the link below.
Windows
Open a fresh instance of cmd.exe under download path and run the following commands (without $)
a) $ RubixOneClickSetup-Windows.exe
b) Provide user password when asked
After the setup is completed open a new command prompt and try the following commands (without $) :
a) $ ipfs &amp;ndash;version</description></item><item><title>Additional rubix review</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/additional-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/additional-review/</guid><description>What are rubix notes? rubix is a pilot program that allows volunteer contributors on Rubix to collaboratively add context (called “notes”) to Tweets they believe could be misleading. The aim is to keep people on Rubix better informed by showing notes that people from different points of view will find helpful.
Notes are only shown to a small set of people in the pilot program, and notes only appear on Tweets when they’ve been rated helpful by enough people from different points of view.</description></item><item><title>Create Decentralized IDentity</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/create-did/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/create-did/</guid><description>Decentralized identity is a trust framework in which identifiers, such as usernames, can be replaced with IDs that are self-owned, independent, and enable data exchange using blockchain technology to protect privacy and secure transactions. As our lives are increasingly linked to apps, devices, and services, we’re often subject to data breaches and privacy loss. A standards-based decentralized identity system can provide greater privacy and control over your data.
Rubix Decentralized IDentity (DID) project is an open standard enabling users to create self-owned identities, and use blockchain networks for getting decentralized tamper proof verifiable claims.</description></item><item><title>Decentralized IDentity</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/did/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/did/</guid><description>DID &amp;amp; its significance DID (Decentralized identity) is a trust framework in which identifiers such as usernames can be replaced with IDs that are self-owned, independent, and enable data exchange using blockchain technology, providing privacy and secure transactions. Our lives are increasingly linked to apps, devices and services, and we’re often subject to data breaches and privacy loss. Hence, a standards-based decentralized identity system can provide greater privacy and control over your data.</description></item><item><title>Downloading data</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/download-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/download-data/</guid><description>We can&amp;rsquo;t wait to learn with you!
All rubix contributions are publicly available on the Download Data page of the rubix site so that anyone in the US has free access to analyze the data, identify problems, and spot opportunities to make rubix better.
If you have questions or feedback about the rubix public data or would like to share your analyses of this data with us, please DM us at @rubixchain.</description></item><item><title>Earn Proof Credits</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/proof-credits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/proof-credits/</guid><description>Validators will accumulate proof credits from various transactions across different Proofchains. A validator node can be choosen as Alpha, Beta or as a Gamma node. Alpha nodes are picked based on the credits they have accumulated. When a node accumilates enough Proof Credits equivalent to the current level, the node can convert the proof credits into one new RBT token. Nodes continue to earn proof credits &amp;amp; thereby mine new RBT tokens by participating in consensus of various transactions &amp;amp; perpetually storing the consensus proofs.</description></item><item><title>Examples</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/examples/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/examples/</guid><description>Great rubix notes follow the program&amp;rsquo;s values: They build understanding, are written in good faith, and are helpful even to those who disagree.
&amp;ldquo;Whales aren&amp;rsquo;t real&amp;rdquo; Here&amp;rsquo;s a Tweet making misleading claims about whales, followed by helpful and unhelpful rubix notes:
Whales are not actually mammals. If Humans (land mammals) can’t drink seawater — just try it! — how can supposed sea mammals like whales stay hydrated?</description></item><item><title>FAQs</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/faq/</guid><description>How many transactions can rubix handle? Popular blockchains (BTC and ETH) work by every node adding transactions to a central chain and the chain grows in one direction with it. Rubix is designed and built as a peer to peer blockchain where a transaction happening from node A to node B is only corresponding quorum nodes are only known and participated in the transaction. Maximum transaction threshold with 10,000 nodes is 150,000.</description></item><item><title>Hot Backups</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/hotbackups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/hotbackups/</guid><description>Hot backup, also known as dynamic or online backup, is performed on data while the database is actively online and accessible to users. It is useful to revert back to the previous state of the node, in the event of an undesired situation.
A backup can be simply done by creating a zip folder of the Wallet and .ipfs folders on your system.
Subsquently, a restore can be done by unzipping the same folders, to restore the previous state of your system (node).</description></item><item><title>How to verify checksum of Rubix files</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/checksum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/checksum/</guid><description>A checksum is a special type of hash that is used to verify the integrity of a file. Verifying a checksum ensures there was no corruption or manipulation during the download and the file was downloaded completely and correctly.
A common use case for checksum verification is to verify a large downloaded file. MD5 and SHA1 hashes are commonly used for this task. We will look at easy ways to obtain a hash to verify a checksum.</description></item><item><title>IPFS and Peer ID</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/ipfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/ipfs/</guid><description>IPFS (Interplanetary File System) IPFS is a relatively new hypermedia protocol and decentralized data storage system that leverages a peer-to-peer (p2p) network architecture.
By comparison, IPFS uses content-based addressing so that content can be verified and decoupled from distant servers, and stored closer to the user. It does that through the use of content identifiers (CIDs), or “labels” which are used to point to material in IPFS. CIDs are generated based on the content’s cryptographic hash, or a function that uses mathematical algorithms to take some arbitrary input and return a fixed-length value.</description></item><item><title>Mine ID</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/mine-id/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/mine-id/</guid><description>Our team is currently busy writing this content, we&amp;rsquo;ll update the contents here soon!!
Whales are not actually mammals. If Humans (land mammals) can’t drink seawater — just try it! — how can supposed sea mammals like whales stay hydrated?
&amp;mdash; rubix Example (@bwatchexample) January 25, 2021 -- If you have questions or feedback, please DM us at @rubixchain.
What happens when the mining level upgrades? Credits required to mine a RBT doubles every time the mining level increases.</description></item><item><title>NFT Deep Dive</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/nft-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/nft-deep-dive/</guid><description>Our team is currently busy writing this content, we&amp;rsquo;ll update the contents here soon!!
Whales are not actually mammals. If Humans (land mammals) can’t drink seawater — just try it! — how can supposed sea mammals like whales stay hydrated?
&amp;mdash; rubix Example (@bwatchexample) January 25, 2021 -- If you have questions or feedback, please DM us at @rubixchain.
What happens when the mining level upgrades? Credits required to mine a RBT doubles every time the mining level increases.</description></item><item><title>NLSS</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/nlss/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/nlss/</guid><description>Our team is currently busy writing this content, we&amp;rsquo;ll update the contents here soon!!
Whales are not actually mammals. If Humans (land mammals) can’t drink seawater — just try it! — how can supposed sea mammals like whales stay hydrated?
&amp;mdash; rubix Example (@bwatchexample) January 25, 2021 -- If you have questions or feedback, please DM us at @rubixchain.
What happens when the mining level upgrades? Credits required to mine a RBT doubles every time the mining level increases.</description></item><item><title>Node</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/node/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/node/</guid><description>What is node? A node in the context of a Blockchain usually refers to a device that downloads the appropriate cryptocurrency software to connect to a network between partners. Any user who has completed the Rubix Network Setup will be a node in the Rubix Network. Rubix node is configured in P2P networks, each device that participates in the network receives the name of node.
The nodes are the individual parts of the largest data structure that is a blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Non Fungible Tokens</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/nft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/nft/</guid><description>NFT&amp;rsquo;s are the new sensation in the world of Blockchain and cryptocurrencies. From the first NFT &amp;ldquo;Quantum&amp;rdquo; being created in 2014 to the latest NFT drop by sports giant Adidas, and to NFT&amp;rsquo;s that are minted on Rubix Platform.
What is an NFT? NFT stands for Non-Fungible Token. The word Fungible means Replaceable, so the meaning of NFT can be interpreted as Non-Replaceable Token, i.e an NFT is unique and each NFT is one of a kind.</description></item><item><title>Oracles</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/oracles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/oracles/</guid><description>Our team is currently busy writing this content, we&amp;rsquo;ll update the contents here soon!!
Whales are not actually mammals. If Humans (land mammals) can’t drink seawater — just try it! — how can supposed sea mammals like whales stay hydrated?
&amp;mdash; rubix Example (@bwatchexample) January 25, 2021 -- If you have questions or feedback, please DM us at @rubixchain.
What happens when the mining level upgrades? Credits required to mine a RBT doubles every time the mining level increases.</description></item><item><title>Private Share</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/private-share/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/private-share/</guid><description>Private Share is the second share/part of a node&amp;rsquo;s Decentalized ID (DID). It is generated during the DID&amp;rsquo;s Share generation process, and it is 8 times the size of the DID. This Share generation process uses a NLSS based cryptographic solution.
Significance: The Private Share is private/secret for a particular node and only that node has its information. Hence, it is an important parameter during different kinds of authentication scenarios.</description></item><item><title>Proof Chain</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/proofchain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/proofchain/</guid><description>The Rubix global state will be made of about 51.4 million Proofchains. Each Proofchain is bound by one unique utility token. A ProofChain PT is made of all transactions that use token Tn to confirm. All transactions within a Proofchain PT are validated individually and sequentially. However, transactions of different Proofchains are validated asynchronously and parallelly.
Whales are not actually mammals. If Humans (land mammals) can’t drink seawater — just try it!</description></item><item><title>Proof of Pledge</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/pledge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/pledge/</guid><description>Rubix introduces the lightweight, low carbon footprint consensus protocol, a superior of Proof of Work (PoW) and Proof of Stake(PoS). Quorum performs work to validate the transaction &amp;amp; verify cryptographic signatures. Quorum earn proof credits in return for the work performed. The credits earned as a result of work are pledged by the Quorum to secure the network using the PoP algorithm. Proof of Pledge (PoP) is the important part of the Rubix Network’s consensus algorithm.</description></item><item><title>Proof-of-Pledge</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/pop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/pop/</guid><description>Proof of pledge is best of both worlds - proof of work and proof of stake. Validators are doing work and earning non transferable proof credits by verifying and signing transactions for the network. This credits are pledged for verifying new transactions (validator will loose credits for signing a bogus transaction). These credits are accumilated to mine token in the network.
Proof-of-Work Is Not Viable in the Long-Term due to its energy consumption.</description></item><item><title>Public Share</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/public-share/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/public-share/</guid><description>Every node joining the Rubix platform creates a unique network Decentralized Identity (DID). This DID is then split into two shares: Public Share and Private Share. The Public Share is also reffered to as the &amp;lsquo;Public Network Share&amp;rsquo;.
Significance: The Public Netwrok Share along with the DID is stored by the node on the IPFS. The IPFS hashes of these two values are then communicated to all peer nodes in the network.</description></item><item><title>Quorum</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/quorum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/quorum/</guid><description>Quorum, as the word defines it is a group of selected peers who are active in the Rubix Network that validate any transcation happening over the network. Token verification and signing is done using Rubix&amp;rsquo;s consensus algorithm &amp;lsquo;Proof of Plegde&amp;rsquo;.
Each Quorum will be awarded an incentive for each successful validation, inorder to be eligible for the incentive they have to Pledge some Token
Learn more about of Proof of Plegde by clicking here.</description></item><item><title>RAC - Rubix Asset Contract</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/rac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/rac/</guid><description>The Rubix Asset Contract (RAC) are rules / guidelines to enable users to develop tokens on top of Rubix Blockchain network resulting in Secondary Layer solutions, Decentralized Applications, NFT&amp;rsquo;s and much more. It is a standard by which users can mint/transfer/verify secondary tokens or NFT&amp;rsquo;s transferd/transaction through the Rubix validator network.
Tokens minted in the Rubix network need to adhere to rules stated in the Rubix Asset Contract. These rules/guidelines may include details on what the token structure should look like, how they can be transfered in the network, validated by the quorum and so on.</description></item><item><title>Signatures and Validation</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/signature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/signature/</guid><description>Our team is currently busy writing this content, we&amp;rsquo;ll update the contents here soon!!
Whales are not actually mammals. If Humans (land mammals) can’t drink seawater — just try it! — how can supposed sea mammals like whales stay hydrated?
&amp;mdash; rubix Example (@bwatchexample) January 25, 2021 -- If you have questions or feedback, please DM us at @rubixchain.
What happens when the mining level upgrades? Credits required to mine a RBT doubles every time the mining level increases.</description></item><item><title>Staking</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/staking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/staking/</guid><description>Our team is currently busy writing this content, we&amp;rsquo;ll update the contents here soon!!
Whales are not actually mammals. If Humans (land mammals) can’t drink seawater — just try it! — how can supposed sea mammals like whales stay hydrated?
&amp;mdash; rubix Example (@bwatchexample) January 25, 2021 -- If you have questions or feedback, please DM us at @rubixchain.
What happens when the mining level upgrades? Credits required to mine a RBT doubles every time the mining level increases.</description></item><item><title>Terminology</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/terminologies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/terminologies/</guid><description>We are trying to explain some of the terminalogoies in simple words, thus you will be able to comprehend the terms more easily and swift through the process with ease
Whales are not actually mammals. If Humans (land mammals) can’t drink seawater — just try it! — how can supposed sea mammals like whales stay hydrated?
&amp;mdash; rubix Example (@bwatchexample) January 25, 2021 -- If you have questions or feedback, please DM us at @rubixchain.</description></item><item><title>Token</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/token/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/token/</guid><description>Our team is currently busy writing this content, we&amp;rsquo;ll update the contents here soon!!
Whales are not actually mammals. If Humans (land mammals) can’t drink seawater — just try it! — how can supposed sea mammals like whales stay hydrated?
&amp;mdash; rubix Example (@bwatchexample) January 25, 2021 -- If you have questions or feedback, please DM us at @rubixchain.
What happens when the mining level upgrades? Credits required to mine a RBT doubles every time the mining level increases.</description></item><item><title>Token Chains</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/tokenchains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/tokenchains/</guid><description>Our team is currently busy writing this content, we&amp;rsquo;ll update the contents here soon!!
Whales are not actually mammals. If Humans (land mammals) can’t drink seawater — just try it! — how can supposed sea mammals like whales stay hydrated?
&amp;mdash; rubix Example (@bwatchexample) January 25, 2021 -- If you have questions or feedback, please DM us at @rubixchain.
What happens when the mining level upgrades? Credits required to mine a RBT doubles every time the mining level increases.</description></item><item><title>Vision</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/vision/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/vision/</guid><description>Rubix is a peer-to-peer, immutable &amp;amp; truly decentralized blockchain platform that can scale significantly with asynchronous parallelism and support real-world decentralized applications. Rubix deploys a superior consensus mechanism ‘Proof-of-Pledge’ (PoP) — a lightweight algorithm, which reduces carbon emissions significantly. The PoP is highly scalable as it can run on laptops, desktops, and other IoT devices. Its on-chain validation makes the network immutable. The platform also offers instant validation and finality of transactions with a speed of 253.</description></item><item><title>Wallet</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/wallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/wallet/</guid><description>Rubix Wallet is secured with decentralized identity management system that allows users to create and manage their own identities and use blockchain networks for getting decentralized tamper proof verifiable claims. The claims are 100% on-chain and publicly verifiable.
-- Prerequisites Rubix Wallet runs on top of Rubix node. Please follow the prerequisites to install IPFS and Java before installing the rubix wallet. Prerequisites for Rubix Node Once the prerequisites are satisfied, install the rubix wallet.</description></item><item><title>What inspired us</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/inspired/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/inspired/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Where to buy Rubix Tokens - RBT</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/buy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/buy/</guid><description>Rubix Tokens are available to purchase in the following exchanges:
Vindax Lbank If you have questions or feedback, please DM us at @rubixchain.</description></item><item><title>📣 What's New</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/whatsnew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/whatsnew/</guid><description>What is new in Rubix Network Here you can find what all are happening in Rubix, get latest updates etc.!!!
🎉 Rubix V1.9.4 We at Rubix has introduced a new staking policy where we ensure for each new RBT mining transaction, 3 out of 5 alpha quorums should pledge 1 RBT for a height of 4 difficulty level . Tokens pledged/staked will earn yield based on demand/supply. The pledge tokens will be available for transfer after completion of 256 transactions (Level 4) from the genesis node of the mined token.</description></item></channel></rss>