<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Learn Rubix</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Learn Rubix</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://learn.rubix.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setup Rubix Node</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/node-setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/node-setup/</guid><description>Nodes in Rubix mine token by utilizing credits earned by validating transactions in the network.
When a new node joins the network, it will have 0 credits and 0 tokens to start with. Over time common pool will pick the node to validate transactions comming to the network. For every transaction that is validated, the node will earn 1 credit. Credits are non transferable and are only used to mine a new RBT token.</description></item><item><title>Additional rubix review</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/additional-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/additional-review/</guid><description>What are rubix notes? rubix is a pilot program that allows volunteer contributors on Rubix to collaboratively add context (called “notes”) to Tweets they believe could be misleading. The aim is to keep people on Rubix better informed by showing notes that people from different points of view will find helpful.
Notes are only shown to a small set of people in the pilot program, and notes only appear on Tweets when they’ve been rated helpful by enough people from different points of view.</description></item><item><title>Create Centralized IDentity</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/create-did/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/create-did/</guid><description>Decentralized identity is a trust framework in which identifiers, such as usernames, can be replaced with IDs that are self-owned, independent, and enable data exchange using blockchain technology to protect privacy and secure transactions. As our lives are increasingly linked to apps, devices, and services, we’re often subject to data breaches and privacy loss. A standards-based decentralized identity system can provide greater privacy and control over your data.
Rubix Decentralized IDentity (DID) project is an open standard enabling users to create self-owned identities, and use blockchain networks for getting decentralized tamper proof verifiable claims.</description></item><item><title>Downloading data</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/download-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/download-data/</guid><description>We can&amp;rsquo;t wait to learn with you!
All rubix contributions are publicly available on the Download Data page of the rubix site so that anyone in the US has free access to analyze the data, identify problems, and spot opportunities to make rubix better.
If you have questions or feedback about the rubix public data or would like to share your analyses of this data with us, please DM us at @rubixchain.</description></item><item><title>Earn Proof Credits</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/proof-credits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/proof-credits/</guid><description>Validators will accumulate proof credits from various transactions across different Proofchains. A validator node can be choosen as Alpha, Beta or as a Gamma node. Alpha nodes are picked based on the credits they have accumulated. When a node accumilates enough Proof Credits equivalent to the current level, the node can convert the proof credits into one new RBT token. Nodes continue to earn proof credits &amp;amp; thereby mine new RBT tokens by participating in consensus of various transactions &amp;amp; perpetually storing the consensus proofs.</description></item><item><title>Examples</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/examples/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/examples/</guid><description>Great rubix notes follow the program&amp;rsquo;s values: They build understanding, are written in good faith, and are helpful even to those who disagree.
&amp;ldquo;Whales aren&amp;rsquo;t real&amp;rdquo; Here&amp;rsquo;s a Tweet making misleading claims about whales, followed by helpful and unhelpful rubix notes:
Whales are not actually mammals. If Humans (land mammals) can’t drink seawater — just try it! — how can supposed sea mammals like whales stay hydrated?</description></item><item><title>FAQs</title><link>https://learn.rubix.net/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learn.rubix.net/faq/</guid><description>How many transactions can rubix handle? Popular blockchains (BTC and ETH) work by every node adding transactions to a central chain and the chain grows in one direction with it. Rubix is designed and built as a peer to peer blockchain where a transaction happening from node A to node B is only corresponding quorum nodes are only known and participated in the transaction. Maximum transaction threshold with 10,000 nodes is 150,000.</description></item></channel></rss>